Cultural Survival Records MS180
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Bazaar and publicity records, 1975 -- 2010; MS180.005; 3.6 Linear Feet
  - Bazaar, 1990 -- 2010; MS180.005.001
    - Bazaar Evaluation, FY2006, MS180.005.001.00002 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Bazaar Financial Report, 2006; MS180.005.001.00003 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Bazaar Fliers, 1990 -- 2005; MS180.005.001.00004 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Bazaars Committee, 2002 -- 2008; MS180.005.001.00005 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Boston & Cambridge Advertising, 2005; MS180.005.001.00006 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Burlington, VT Latino Festival, 2006; MS180.005.001.00007 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Creative Works, 2003; MS180.005.001.00008 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - CS Bazaar Rocco, 1999; MS180.005.001.00009 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - December 13-14 Bazaar Map, MS180.005.001.00010 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Email correspondence regarding funding, 2008 -- 2009; MS180.005.001.00011 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - GALA Bazaar, 1999 -- 2000; MS180.005.001.00012 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Hynes Bazaar, 2000 -- 2010; MS180.005.001.00013 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - The Lacandon Children's Art Workshop, 1996 -- 1998; MS180.005.001.00014 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Media/PR Contact Cards [1 of 2], 1993; MS180.005.001.00015 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Media/PR Contact Cards [2 of 2], 1993; MS180.005.001.00016 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - New York City UNPF Bazaar, 2003 -- 2004; MS180.005.001.00017 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Northampton Bazaar, 2005; MS180.005.001.00018 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Photographs, 2001; MS180.005.001.00019 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Plimouth Plantation, 2006; MS180.005.001.00020 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Pound Hall Bazaar, 2005; MS180.005.001.00021 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Providence Bazaar, 2005; MS180.005.001.00022 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Sample items, 2005; MS180.005.001.00023 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Summer Vendors, 2006; MS180.005.001.00024 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Tiverton - Bazaar, 2004; MS180.005.001.00025 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Training Materials, 2010; MS180.005.001.00026 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Unfiled, 1990 -- 2005; MS180.005.001.00027 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Winter Vendor Applications, 2005; MS180.005.001.00028 (Box MS180 Shared 5)
    - Cultural Survival Bazaar, 1990-12; MS180.005.002.00001 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      videocassette
    - Cultural Survival: Summer Bazaar, 1990 -- 1995; MS180.005.002.00002 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Mini-DV videos from Bazaars, 2002 -- 2004; MS180.005.002.00003 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      - Bazaar Tiverton, 2004-08; MS180.005.002.00003.00001 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
        Mini-DV
      - Scott Braman One Sky presentation, 2003; MS180.005.002.00003.00002 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      - Tape #5 Bazaar, 2002-05-19; MS180.005.002.00003.00003 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      - Tiverton Bazaar Yarina, 2004-08-01; MS180.005.002.00003.00004 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Tape of Cultural Survival Bazaar Jackie Shohet, 1990-12; MS180.005.002.00004 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Publicity, 1975 -- 2010; MS180.005.002
    - Cultural Survival slideshows I and II, 1975 -- 1985; MS180.005.002.00005 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      Contains slides from two promotional slide shows. Likely not complete sets of either.
    - Project Letimaren (PUMAREN): Planning for the Future Slide Show: Tray # 1, 1989; MS180.005.002.00006 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Project Letimaren audio, 1990; MS180.005.002.00007 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      Contains Spanish-language "old" version, English language version, and music mix master.
    - Cultural Survival PSA, 1990-08-03; MS180.005.002.00008 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      audio tape
    - Cultural Survival PSA, 1990-08-09; MS180.005.002.00009 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival television advertisement, 1990; MS180.005.002.00010 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      0:30 advertisement.
    - People and Rain Forests, 1991; MS180.005.002.00011 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      12:24 video created in collaboration with The Slide Center, Inc. Discusses "importance of using forests sustainably - rain forest facts, resources"
    - Hill, Holliday Advertising "Cultural Survival Second", 1990; MS180.005.002.00012 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      60 second advertisement spot
    - Cultural Survival fundraising advertisement, 1980 -- 1995; MS180.005.002.00013 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      Duplicate copy.
    - Cultural Survival fundraising advertisement, 1980 -- 1995; MS180.005.002.00014 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show soundtrack, 1983; MS180.005.002.00015 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show soundtrack, 1983; MS180.005.002.00016 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show soundtrack music only, 1983; MS180.005.002.00017 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show soundtrack music only, 1983; MS180.005.002.00018 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show soundtrack tape master (Wollensak), 1983; MS180.005.002.00019 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Celebrity Time, Pam Solo & Pia Maybury-Lewis, Tunnel Radio, 1992-01; MS180.005.002.00020 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Pia Maybury-Lewis - Michelle McKinley, 1985 -- 1995; MS180.005.002.00021 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - People and Rain Forests slide show, 1991; MS180.005.002.00022 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      Complete set.
    - People and Rain Forest slide show correspondence, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.005.002.00023 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Cultural Survival Slide Show, 1987; MS180.005.002.00024 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
      Complete set of slides and copy of print advertisement for show.
    - Flyers, brochures, and other promotional materials, 1980 -- 2010; MS180.005.002.00025 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    - Calendars, 1991 -- 1994; MS180.005.002.00026 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
    - Nomads of Tibet calendar, 2005; MS180.005.002.00027 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
- Millennium records, 1979 -- 1996; MS180.006; 6.25 Linear Feet
  This series consists of correspondence, research files, promotional materials, contracts, video tapes, and audio tapes relating to the 1992 British and US public television video series Millennium: Tribal Wisdom and the Modern World, hosted by and focused on the work of David Maybury-Lewis. Material dates chiefly from 1988-1992. Cultural Survival's contribution was limited to promoting the series to its networks of members and at several publicity events across the nation, a role that is reflected in the correspondence. A few records indicate various staff members' interest in being included in the television series – including a letter from Jason Clay to the Cultural Survival Board of Directors, circa 1987, proposing that Cultural Survival take on Millennium as a Special Project. Maybury-Lewis's correspondence documents his roles as co-creator, narrator, and adviser on issues such as the script, partnerships, production and post-production work, and fundraising; and includes letters to and from a number of public figures, including Claude Lévi-Strauss, Ursula K. Le Guin, and former Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution Robert McCormick Adams, Jr.. The series also contains a number of research files on indigenous peoples considered for inclusion in the show, videocassettes of the program, and audio tapes of the show's soundtrack.
  - A Poor Man... Research Notes, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Aborigines, 1989; MS180.006.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Board Letters & Invitations, 1988; MS180.006.001.00003 (Box 1)
    Includes copies of letters to and from Claude Lévi-Strauss, Paul Samuelson, Robert McCormick Adams, Jr., Barbara Tuchman, and Alfonso Ortiz.
  - Advisory Board / Thanks for Acceptance, 1988; MS180.006.001.00004 (Box 1)
    Includes copies and originals of letters to and from Claude Lévi-Strauss, Robert McCormick Adams, Jr., and Alfonso Ortiz.
  - Andaman Islanders, 1989; MS180.006.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Ann Forbes - Ecology, 1989; MS180.006.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Annabel Huxley / Viking London, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Art of Living research notes, 1983 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Body Shop - Australia, 1992; MS180.006.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Body Shop - UK / Millennium, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Cargo Cults, 1989; MS180.006.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Chie Nakane, 1984; MS180.006.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Columbus, 1990; MS180.006.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Contact Lists, 1989 -- 1992; MS180.006.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Core Groups, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Core Groups report [1 of 2], 1989; MS180.006.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Core Groups report [2 of 2], 1989; MS180.006.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988 -- 1989; MS180.006.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Cost Statements, 1987; MS180.006.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Cravath, Swaine & Moore, 1984; MS180.006.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Credit Rolls, 1991; MS180.006.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - CS millennium publicity, 1991; MS180.006.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Cultural Survival / Millennium - Jason Clay letter to Board of Directors, 1987; MS180.006.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Cuna, 1989; MS180.006.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - David's Spiel, 1988 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - DM-L Interview, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - DM-L Personal Story: Millennium, 1988; MS180.006.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Ecology, 1988 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Ecology of Mind research notes, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Ecology of the Mind Ex. from Indigenous Societies, 1983 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Educational Outreach, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Episode One: The Shock of the Other, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Episode treatments, 1991; MS180.006.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Episode Two: An Ecology of Mind, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - European Trip, 1990; MS180.006.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Expenses, 1987 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Expenses / PR Trips, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - First Contact by Renato Rosaldo, 1989; MS180.006.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - First Contact / Peru, 1989; MS180.006.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Gabra, 1989; MS180.006.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - General Treatment, 1983; MS180.006.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Giancarlo Ligabue, 1979 -- 1985; MS180.006.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Gnosticism, 1990; MS180.006.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Humla, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Individualism, 1990; MS180.006.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Indonesia - Grand Komodo Tours, 1990; MS180.006.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Inventing Reality, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Inventing Reality (1) Research Notes, 1990; MS180.006.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Inventing Reality (2) Research on Quantum Theory, 1990; MS180.006.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Kalash Kafir, 1989; MS180.006.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - KCET Event, 1992; MS180.006.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - KCET Outreach correspondence and drafts, 1991; MS180.006.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Macuna / Tukano, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Makuna Tukano, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Meech & Grant / Correspondence, 1982 -- 1984; MS180.006.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Millennium, 1992; MS180.006.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Biniman Production Details, 1990; MS180.006.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / Body Shop, 1992; MS180.006.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / Body Shop Australia Office, 1992; MS180.006.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Book, 1991; MS180.006.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Book Tour - US, 1992; MS180.006.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Millennium book uncorrected proof, 1992; MS180.006.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Millennium books, 1992; MS180.006.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Clippings, 1992; MS180.006.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Clippings - Australia, 1992; MS180.006.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Clippings - Canada, 1992; MS180.006.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Commercial Video Distrib., 1991; MS180.006.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Contacts, 1991; MS180.006.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Contracts, 1988 -- 1989; MS180.006.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Copyright, 1992; MS180.006.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / CS Budget, 1990 -- 1991; MS180.006.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / CS Collaboration, 1991; MS180.006.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / CS Collaboration|Millenium Action & Resource Guide, 1991; MS180.006.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / CS Collaboration|Millennium Public Relations, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Millennium / David's role + DM-L Outline (12 pages), 1989; MS180.006.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Education and Action, 1991; MS180.006.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Episode Outlines, 1991; MS180.006.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Event Announcements, 1992; MS180.006.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Event - Boston, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Event - L.A., 1992; MS180.006.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Event - San Francisco, 1992; MS180.006.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Event - San Francisco|San Francisco Event - Invite Letters, 1992; MS180.006.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Events, 1992; MS180.006.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Funding, 1989 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: General, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - General Interest, 1993 -- 1994; MS180.006.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Millennium in Japan, 1993; MS180.006.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Info on Tribes, 1991; MS180.006.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - Japan, 1992; MS180.006.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: KCET Contract, 1991; MS180.006.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: KCET Meetings, 1991; MS180.006.002.00038 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Mail - Letters to DML [1 of 2], 1992 -- 1993; MS180.006.002.00039 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Mail - Letters to DML [2 of 2], 1992 -- 1993; MS180.006.002.00040 (Box 2)
    Includes letter by Ursula K. Le Guin, among others.
  - Millennium Matters newsletter, 1990; MS180.006.002.00041 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Neighborhood Anthropology Contest, 1992; MS180.006.002.00042 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - notes, mtgs., 1991; MS180.006.002.00043 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Payments to DM-L, 1989; MS180.006.002.00044 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: PBS Program Policies, 1990; MS180.006.002.00045 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Press, 1992; MS180.006.002.00046 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Press: PBS Press Tour, 1992; MS180.006.002.00047 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Press Kits, 1992; MS180.006.002.00048 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Press Reviews, 1992; MS180.006.002.00049 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Project Overviews, 1991; MS180.006.002.00050 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Publicity, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00051 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - Requests for review copies, 1992; MS180.006.002.00052 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Resource & Action Guide, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.002.00053 (Box 2)
  - Millennium Response, 1992; MS180.006.002.00054 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - Reviews, 1992; MS180.006.002.00055 (Box 2)
  - Millennium: Shepley Winings, 1992; MS180.006.002.00056 (Box 2)
  - Millennium - Similar Series, 1990; MS180.006.002.00057 (Box 2)
  - Millennium soundtrack: cassette tapes, 1992; MS180.006.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Student Activity Sheets, 1992; MS180.006.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Talking Points, 1992; MS180.006.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Millennium Teacher's Tips, 1992; MS180.006.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: the Book [1 of 3], 1991; MS180.006.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: the Book [2 of 3], 1991; MS180.006.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: the Book [3 of 3], 1991; MS180.006.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Tribal Wisdom and the Modern World Press Clippings [1 of 3], 1992; MS180.006.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Tribal Wisdom and the Modern World Press Clippings [2 of 3], 1992; MS180.006.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Tribal Wisdom and the Modern World Press Clippings [3 of 3], 1992; MS180.006.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Millennium - Tribes Biblio., 1991; MS180.006.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Millennium: Viewers Guide, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Millennium / Walpiri (Matthew Flanagan), 1992; MS180.006.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Mistaken I.D.: Research Notes, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - National Millennium Series Outreach Packet, 1992; MS180.006.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Poor Man, 1989; MS180.006.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Press Contacts, 1992; MS180.006.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Press - Millennium, 1992; MS180.006.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Promotional material, 1992; MS180.006.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Prospects: Millennium / Cultural Survival, 1990 -- 1991; MS180.006.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Research for New York Trip July 1990: Correspondence, MS180.006.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Samburu, 1990; MS180.006.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - SBS / David Robinson, 1992; MS180.006.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - SBS Millennium press and publicity packet, 1992; MS180.006.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Shavante, 1990; MS180.006.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Shepley-Winings, 1991 -- 1992; MS180.006.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Strange Relations Research Notes, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Sumba, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Thailand Hill Tribes, 1989; MS180.006.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Threshold - Research Notes, 1990; MS180.006.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Tightrope of Power Research Notes [1 of 2], 1990 -- 1991; MS180.006.003.00031 (Box 3)
  - Tightrope of Power Research Notes [2 of 2], 1990 -- 1991; MS180.006.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Timeless, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Toraja, 1989; MS180.006.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Toronto - Business: Production and Post-Production details, 1990; MS180.006.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - Touching the Timeless Research Notes, 1989 -- 1990; MS180.006.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - Transcripts of Films / Peru, Brazil, 1990; MS180.006.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Translations, 1991; MS180.006.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Victor Barac Navajo Reading Notes, 1990; MS180.006.003.00039 (Box 3)
  - Video promo: "Millennium is a Highway", 1991-12-20; MS180.006.003.00040 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
    Length: 4:22 mins.
  - Videos: KCET Television "Milennium Promo" Length 12:00, 1992; MS180.006.004.00001 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Videos: Millennium, Episode 4 duplicates, 1992; MS180.006.004.00002 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Videos: Millennium, Episode 10 duplicate, 1992; MS180.006.004.00003 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Videos: Millennium, Episodes 1-4, 1992; MS180.006.004.00004 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Videos: Millennium, Episodes 5-6, 9-10, 1992; MS180.006.004.00005 (Box MS180 Shared 6)
  - Viewer's Guide, 1991; MS180.006.004.00006 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
  - Wayuu, 1989; MS180.006.004.00007 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
  - Weber: Notes / Xeroxes for Poor Man, 1990 -- 1991; MS180.006.004.00008 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
  - WGBH Millennium Event Correspondence, 1992; MS180.006.004.00009 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
  - Wodaabe, 1989 -- 1991; MS180.006.004.00010 (Box MS180 Shared 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars - David Maybury-Lewis "Tribal Wisdom and the Modern World" interview, 1996-01-15; MS180.006.004.00011 (Case MS180 Shared 4)
- Cultural Survival Quarterly records, 1980 -- 2011; MS180.007; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series consists of Cultural Survival Quarterly (CSQ) issue number-specific working files, correspondence, and papers relating to the production of the magazine, 1980-2011. CSQ issue number files, 1993-2002, contain records related to the production of specific issues of the magazine. Correspondence, 1980-2011, is largely between Cultural Survival staff and authors or guest editors who contributed to CSQ. Correspondence also concerns article reprint permissions, review materials, advertising, issue planning, administration of the magazine, staff policies, photographs and image rights, intern training materials, popular feedback, printing, and distribution.
  This series is arranged into two groups: CSQ issue number files and Correspondence. CSQ issue number files are arranged chronologically by issue number. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically.
  - CSQ issue number file, 1993 -- 2002; MS180.007.001
    - 18(4): GIS, 1993 -- 1994; MS180.007.001.00001 (Box 1)
    - 18(4) Logo Requests, 1994; MS180.007.001.00002 (Box 1)
    - 18(4) Production Notes, 1994 -- 1995; MS180.007.001.00003 (Box 1)
    - 19.1 Women & War, 1994 -- 1995; MS180.007.001.00004 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Correspondence - Guest Editor Danny Danforth, 1994 -- 1995; MS180.007.001.00005 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Editorial, 1995; MS180.007.001.00006 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - EE Briefly Noted, 1995; MS180.007.001.00007 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Invoices, 1995; MS180.007.001.00008 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Misc. Stuff Sent to Contributors, 1994; MS180.007.001.00009 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Permissions, 1994 -- 1995; MS180.007.001.00010 (Box 1)
    - 19.2 E. Europe - Research Material, 1994; MS180.007.001.00011 (Box 1)
    - 19-3, 1995 -- 1998; MS180.007.001.00012 (Box 1)
    - 19:3 Colin McKenzie, Meredith Sandler, 1995; MS180.007.001.00013 (Box 1)
    - 19(3) Culture Resources & Conflict, 1993 -- 1995; MS180.007.001.00014 (Box 1)
    - 19:4, Correspondence for, 1996; MS180.007.001.00015 (Box 1)
    - 19(4) Native American Religious Freedoms, 1995 -- 1996; MS180.007.001.00016 (Box 1)
    - 19(4) Permissions, 1995; MS180.007.001.00017 (Box 1)
    - 20-1 Common Properties, 1995 -- 1996; MS180.007.001.00018 (Box 1)
    - 20-1 Promo, 1995 -- 1996; MS180.007.001.00019 (Box 1)
    - 20-2: Genes, People and Property, 1996; MS180.007.001.00020 (Box 1)
    - 20-2 Blueline corrections & late add-ons, 1996; MS180.007.001.00021 (Box 1)
    - 20-2 Friedlander - Gene Patent, 1995 -- 1997; MS180.007.001.00022 (Box 1)
    - 20-3: "Who's Local Here?" Politics of Participation in Development, 1996; MS180.007.001.00023 (Box 1)
    - 20-4: Traditional Music in Community Life, 1996; MS180.007.001.00024 (Box 1)
    - 21-1 Admin, 1996 -- 1997; MS180.007.001.00025 (Box 1)
    - 21-1: Museums & Rep., 1996 -- 1997; MS180.007.001.00026 (Box 1)
    - 21-2: 25 Years of the Indigenous Movement: The Americas and Australia, 1997; MS180.007.001.00027 (Box 1)
    - 21-3: 25 Years of the Indigenous Movement: Africa and Asia, 1997; MS180.007.001.00028 (Box 1)
    - 21-3: Budget and Permissions, 1997; MS180.007.001.00029 (Box 1)
    - 21-4: The Internet and Indigenous Groups, 1997 -- 1998; MS180.007.001.00030 (Box 1)
    - 22.1 Advertising, 1997 -- 1998; MS180.007.001.00031 (Box 1)
    - 22.1 Intro Ed., Resources, 1997 -- 1998; MS180.007.001.00032 (Box 1)
    - 22.2: Aboriginal Media, Aboriginal Control, 1998; MS180.007.001.00033 (Box 1)
    - 22-3: Crisis on the Last Frontier, 1998; MS180.007.001.00034 (Box 1)
    - 22-4: Uprooted: Disposession in Africa, 1998; MS180.007.001.00035 (Box 1)
    - 23-1 Articles and Resources, 1998 -- 1999; MS180.007.001.00036 (Box 1)
    - 23-1: Indigenous Rights and Self-determination in Mexico, 1997 -- 1999; MS180.007.001.00037 (Box 1)
    - 23-2: Protecting Indigenous Culture and Land through Ecotourism, 1998 -- 1999; MS180.007.001.00038 (Box 1)
    - 23/4: Visions of the Future: The Prospect for Reconciliation, 1999; MS180.007.001.00039 (Box 1)
    - 24-1 Correspondence, 1999 -- 2000; MS180.007.001.00040 (Box 1)
    - 24(2) Admin, 2000; MS180.007.001.00041 (Box 1)
    - 24(2) Correspondence, 1999 -- 2000; MS180.007.001.00042 (Box 1)
    - 24(2) Permissions, 2000; MS180.007.001.00043 (Box 1)
    - 24/2 PR, 2000; MS180.007.001.00044 (Box 1)
    - 24:3: Burma, 2000; MS180.007.001.00045 (Box 1)
    - 24:4 Background, 1998 -- 2000; MS180.007.001.00046 (Box 1)
    - 24:4 Bio Sheets, 2000; MS180.007.001.00047 (Box 1)
    - 24/4 Intellectual Property Rights: Culture as Commodity, 1999 -- 2001; MS180.007.001.00048 (Box 1)
    - 25:1 Mining Issue, 2000 -- 2001; MS180.007.001.00049 (Box 1)
    - 25:2 Endangered Languages, 2000 -- 2001; MS180.007.001.00050 (Box 1)
    - 25:3 From Our Readers, 2000 -- 2001; MS180.007.001.00051 (Box 1)
    - 25:4 Maroons in the Americas, 2000 -- 2001; MS180.007.001.00052 (Box 1)